Stephen Codd

T: +971 55 571 8636 E: grandpoisson@gmail.com

Professional Profile

An accomplished engineer with over thirty years of experience in flight simulation. High level of IT literacy, both hardware and software. Analytical problem solver with a systematic approach to providing on time results. A very good communicator at all levels and possesses good, demonstrable mentoring and training skills. I have achieved project management success through credibility of work. Seeking a career change and a new challenge in a web developer role in a technically diverse environment. Currently studying Full Stack Web Developer course with Code Institute.

Key Skills

- **Leadership:** Constantly monitoring performance of the team and the practices within the team to ensure an effective and efficient operating culture. Ensure that the experience of the group is assimilated to newer less experienced members.
- Communicating: Encourage two-way communication by asking questions and listening to
 the responses. Prepare reports and written work in a concise and structured manner.
 Moderate the tone, body language and content of messages to the needs of the
 individual. Strive to ensure my audience/stakeholders are engaged and fully aware of the
 message and its' intent.
- Attention to Detail: Concerned with always maintaining high standards of accuracy and quality. Periodically evolving practices and procedures to the benefit of the group.
 Proactive in improving project management processes where I believe improvements can be made.
- Achieving Results: Have throughout my career endeavoured to provide solutions and demonstrate a 'can do' attitude. Proactively involves the whole team to achieve desired results.

Career Highlights

2010 - Present: Emirates Airline, Dubai.

Device caretaker for several Boeing B777-300ER flight simulators and software controller for the same. Ensuring the software integrity and fidelity of the devices conform to the latest EASA standards of JAR STD-1A. Perform preventative and corrective maintenance on all areas of training equipment (in line with departmental Quality system) including, but not limited to, Motion and Control Loading systems (hydraulic and electric), Visual projection and display systems, computer host and network systems, software modifications, associated electronic interfaces and power generation systems. Heavily involved in developing improved processes and techniques to make maximum use of limited time resources. Mentoring junior staff and newly recruited UAE nationals as part of a company initiative to develop UAE nationals.

2008 - 2010 Q4 Services, UK.

Operations Manager with a visual display and optics support company managing a workshop that provided customer service support in both Europe and the Middle East. Typical products were CRT refurbishments for high value electronic display systems and large field of view optical systems, while typical services involved assisting customers with the fault finding and calibration of complex electronic display systems. I managed initial contact with potential customers, sales and post-sales support.

1995 -2008 Emirates Airline, Dubai.

Senior Engineer and shift supervisor providing mentoring and leadership to a team of simulator engineers maintaining a fleet of flight training devices. Project managed introduction of new devices from RFQ to customer acceptance.

1990 -1995 British Midland Airways, UK.

Senior Engineer providing expertise and leadership to a team of simulator engineers maintaining a Redifusion 737-300 Flight simulator.

1979 – 1990 Royal Air Force, UK.

Primarily employed as an Avionics technician on the Tornado GR1 simulation and became involved with the EW/RHWR simulation.

Credentials

BTEC Aerospace Studies - Avionics.

BTEC HNC Computer Studies

PRINCE 2 Foundation/Practitioner certified

Currently studying Code Institute Full Stack Web Developer curriculum online.